Guide to the Henry Marie Brackenridge and Family Papers, 1816-1889 DAR.1937.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Henry Marie Brackenridge, Professional Correspondence, 1817-1868; I.
  - James Gadsden to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 104), January 12, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Gadsden, writing from Tallahassee, Florida, to Pensacola, Florida, outlines the founding principles for the Florida Institute of Agriculture, Antiquities and Science. He mentions a second letter to be enclosed, which is located in Folder 43. 4 p. unsigned
  - Joseph M. White, to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 108), November 4, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    White, writing from St. Augustine, Florida, to Pensacola, Florida, asks for assistance with a proposed canal in Florida. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Robert Mitchell to James H. Simpson (LB# 77), November 22, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Mitchell, writing from Pensacola, Florida, introduces Simpson to H.M. Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - James Innerarity to Colin Mitchell (LB# 38), November 25, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Innerarity, writing from Pensacola, Florida, introduces Mitchell to H.M. Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - James Innerarity to Robert Morison (LB# 53), November 25, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Innerarity, writing from Pensacola, Florida, introduces Morison to H.M. Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - William Pope Duval to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 49), November 30, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Duval, writing from Tallahassee, Florida, to Pensacola, Florida, claims he does not believe H.M. Brackenridge to be the author of a critical article on him that appeared in a newspaper. He invites H.M. Brackenridge to attend a land sale and wishes to secure some advice on matters relating to the territory. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - George Walton to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 43), December 11, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Walton, written from Washington, D.C., to Tallahassee, Florida, appeals for help after being charged with stealing funds from the Florida treasury. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - William C. Magruder to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 87), December 21, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Magruder, writing from Baltimore, Maryland, to Pensacola, Florida, praises H.M. Brackenridge's eulogy of Adams and Jefferson. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Samuel R. Overton to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 56), January 28, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Overton, writing from Pensacola, Florida, to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, discusses Florida politics and history. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Samuel R. Overton to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 34), August 18, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Overton, writing from Pensacola, Florida, to Tallahassee, Florida, describes his land in Florida and a recent illness. [Overton succumbed to Yellow Fever two weeks later]. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - John Marshall to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 45), November 19, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Marshall, writing from Richmond, Virginia, to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, informs H.M. Brackenridge that the position of Reporter of the Supreme Court for the United States, for which he had applied, has been filled. 2p. A.L.S.
  - Joseph Story to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 47), November 28, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Story, writing from Salem, Massachusetts, to Washington, D.C., replies to H.M. Brackenridge's inquiry regarding a vacancy in the office of reporter to the United States Supreme Court. Story notes the abundance of well-qualified applicants for the position. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - William Johnson to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 112), December 5, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Johnson, writing from Charleston, South Carolina, to Washington, D.C., states that the position of Reporter of the United States Supreme Court has been filled by another candidate. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - James Clark to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 84), December 23, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Clark, writing from Baltimore, Maryland, to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, looks forward to seeing H.M. Brackenridge, his cousin, in Baltimore. Clark also mentions visits he has arranged with mutual friends and family affairs. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Edward Everett to Joseph M. White (LB# 89), April 23, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Everett, writing from Washington, D.C., forwards payment for an article by H.M. Brackenridge published in the North American Review. [White was the Florida delegate to Congress.] 1 p. A.L.S.
  - James Innerarity to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 107), May 15, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    An invitation to H.M. Brackenridge for the wedding of Innerarity's daughter. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Henry Clay to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 118), June 4, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Clay, writing from Washington, D.C., to Pensacola, Florida, notifies H.M. Brackenridge of his appointment as federal judge of West Florida. 1 p. L.S.
  - Thomas Cooper to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 111), April 12, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    Cooper, writing from Columbus, South Carolina, to Pensacola, Florida, seeks advice about opening a school in Florida. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Duncan L. Clinch to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 12), undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Clinch, writing to H.M. Brackenridge in Pensacola, Florida, requests a return letter from H.M. Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Duncan L. Clinch to James Clarke (LB# 98), May 20, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Clinch's letter serves as an introduction for Clarke to H.M. Brackenridge. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Richard R. Keen to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 100), June 29, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Keen, writing from Baltimore, Maryland, to Washington, D.C., expresses regret at missing a chance to meet with H.M. Brackenridge in Baltimore. He also requests information concerning land sales in Florida. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - John Shoemaker Tyson to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 35), August 27, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Tyson, writing from Baltimore, Maryland, to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, outlines changes he wishes to make to the soon-to-be published account of his speech on the "Jew Bill." The speech is part of an anthology H.M. Brackenridge intends to publish on the controversial legislation. Tyson also mentions Andrew Jackson's ill health and his criticisms of John C. Calhoun. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Peleg Sprague to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 101), September 18, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Scope and Contents note
    Sprague, writing from Hollowell, Maine, to Pensacola, Florida, praises H.M. Brackenridge's recent publication on the "Jew Bill." 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Edward Livingston to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 113), August 20, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Livingston, writing from Montgomery Place, New York, expresses his pleasure with H.M. Brackenridge's approval of the President's Cabinet. He also praises the members for their qualifications and ability to work with one another. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Roger Brooke Taney to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 115), September 10, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Taney, writing from Washington, D.C., thanks H.M. Brackenridge for his note of congratulations on appointment as Attorney General in President Jackson's cabinet. Taney also discusses the position and how he came to receive it. [Taney later became Chief Justice of the Supreme Court and wrote the decision for the Court in the Dred Scott case.] 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Edward Livingston to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 109), September 30, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Livingston, writing from Washington, D.C., refers to the state of affairs in Florida. Livingston discusses the "spirit of espionage" that, according to H.M. Brackenridge, prevailed in Florida. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Andrew Jackson drafts, June-July 1832 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Folders 01-03 incorporate a series of letters mostly addressed to Andrew Jackson. They seem to be drafts of public letters that were eventually published in various newspapers. They were written after H.M. Brackenridge lost his position as judge in West Florida, having been replaced by a political ally of the Jackson administration. The letters contain strong criticisms of the President and his policies. Also included are some of Jackson's replies (copied in H.M. Brackenridge's hand). [Refer to Honeycutt, "The Letters of H.M. and H.H. Brackenridge in the Pittsburgh Archives, 1796-1868", q E353.1 B65A4 1986.]
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Andrew Jackson drafts, July 1832 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    A continuation of the series described above, this folder contains four more drafts of letters addressed to Jackson. They mostly criticize Jackson's actions in Florida.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Andrew Jackson drafts, July 1832 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Four more drafts of letters addressed to Jackson along with one addressed to the voters of Allegheny County.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Levi Woodbury Draft, August 12, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Writing from Tarentum, Pennsylvania, H.M. Brackenridge addresses concerns about land in Deer Point, Florida, that he sold to the Navy. [Woodbury was secretary of the Navy at the time.]
  - Alexander Porter to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 31), January 31, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Porter, writing from Washington, D.C., discusses the banking crisis and Porter's election to the United States Senate. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - William Henry Harrison to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 44), February 2, 1836 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Harrison, writing from Cincinnati, Ohio, to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, discusses a book that concerned a military campaign in which he was involved. He also comments on his presidential campaign. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Virgil David to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 75), March 11, 1836 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    David, writing from Lawrenceville, Pennsylvania, to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, requests a donation of books to the Lawrenceville Lyceum. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - T. Baltzell to H. M. Brackenridge (LB # 103), September 6, 1836 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Baltzell, writing from New York, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, discusses affairs in Florida. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - John B. Hearne to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 96), February 27, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Hearne, writing from Chillicothe, Ohio, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, mentions an edition of Hugh Henry Brackenridge's novel, Modern Chivalry. He also notes that he is looking forward to future writings by H.M. Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - M. M. Wall to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 25), March 3, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    M.M. Wall, writing from New York, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, references a publication of H.M. Brackenridge 's. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - T. Baltzell to H. M. Brackenridge, September 12, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Baltzell writes to H.M. Brackenridge at Tarentum, Pennsylvania about land sales. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - H. Snyder, et al to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 28), July 21, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Snyder, writing from Jefferson College at Canonsburg, Pennsylvania, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, forwards an invitation to H.M. Brackenridge to address a meeting of the "Philo and Franklin Literary Societies" at the college. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Richard Biddle and Charles Naylor to H. M. Brackenridge (LB # 97), January 15, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    The authors, writing from Washington, D.C., to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, outline their thoughts on resolutions adopted by the citizens of East Deer Township, Pennsylvania. 2 p.
  - William Elders to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 11), March 5, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Elders, addressing this letter to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, requests H.M. Brackenridge to speak before the Wirt Institute. 4 p. A.L.S.
  - R. H. Forrester, et al to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 29), March 6, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    The authors, writing from Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, forward an invitation to address the Wirt Institute. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Rufus S. Reed, et al to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 42), July 7, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    The authors, writing from Erie, Pennsylvania, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, forward an invitation to a celebration at the Tippecanoe Club. The invitation is signed by Rufus S. Reed, Thomas H. Sill, John H. Walker, William M. Watts, Joseph M. Sterrett, Charles M. Kelso, A. Scoot, and S. H. Haskind. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Adam Gordon to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 81), July 14, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Gordon, writing from Key West, Florida, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, mentions H.M. Brackenridge's prospects as a candidate for Congress, and other upcoming elections. The letter also discusses conditions in Florida, particularly in Key West. He notes the need for a railroad and better control of banks. Gordon also states that the Seminole War has cut off communication with the mainland. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Adam Gordon to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 76), September 29, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Gordon, writing from Key West, Florida, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, remarks on the danger from the Seminoles and the coming presidential election, which he believes William Henry Harrison will win. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - Stephen Duncan to H. M. Brackenridge, December 7, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Duncan, writing from Natchez, Mississippi, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, congratulates H.M. Brackenridge on his election to Congress. He also lobbies for H.M. Brackenridge's support on a resolution concerning economic relief for bondsmen that is before the House of Representatives. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - John Baldwin to H. M. Brackenridge (LB # 62), August 23, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Baldwin, writing from Washington, D.C., to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, notes Brackenridge's appointment to the Mexican Claims Commission. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Charles M. Dupuy to H. M. Brackenridge, September 24, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Dupuy, writing from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Washington, D.C., informs H.M. Brackenridge of a chaplaincy position that he had applied for twelve years earlier. He requests H.M. Brackenridge to present his application to President Tyler. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to George Haslet (LB # 46), December 15, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    H.M. Brackenridge, writing from Washington, D.C., to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, outlines concerns about his farm. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Frances and John Vance to H. M. Brackenridge, December 21, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    The Vances, writing from Tarentum, Pennsylvania, to Washington D.C., describe the activities of various people in the Tarentum area. They inform H.M. Brackenridge that their father sued Samuel Wolf and Jacob Staley for damaging his property. The second half of the letter is written to Benjamin Morgan. Frances asks Benjamin Morgan if he plans to return to school. 3 p. A.L.S.
  - David Hoffman to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 68), February 9, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Writing from Washington, D.C., Hoffman alludes to a claim apparently brought before the Mexican Claims Commission. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - David Hoffman to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 02), undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Hoffman, writing from Washington D.C., asks to see Governor Marcy's opinion on a report that was before the Mexican Claims Commission. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - John Quincy Adams to H. M. Brackenridge (LB # 67), undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    A copy of a eulogy Adams gave for Lewis Williams, who was a congressman from North Carolina. 2 p.
  - William O. Slade to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 40), April 10, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    In this brief letter, Slade formally apologizes for his conduct at a dinner at which H.M. Brackenridge was present. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - James Kay Jr. to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 74), April 22, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Kay, writing from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Washington, D.C., reveals his plans for the publication of a book. He describes how the financial difficulties facing the country at the time have affected business. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Roger Brooke Taney to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 114), May 10, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Taney, writing from Baltimore, Maryland, to Tarentum Pennsylvania, thanks H.M. Brackenridge for a copy of his "Essay on Trusts and Trustees." 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Lewis J. Cist to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 26), October 5, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Cist, writing from Cincinnati, Ohio, to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, mentions a package of autographed letters sent by H.M. Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - William Darlington to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 27), September 16, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Darlington, writing from West Chester, Pennsylvania, to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, forwards this letter along with a copy of Darlington's book, Reliquiae Baldwinianae, which has just been published. William Baldwin, the subject of the book, traveled with H.M. Brackenridge on his voyage to South America. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - John Kelly to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 82), September 30, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Kelly, writing from Allegheny City, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, discusses local politics and his job as secretary of the Allegheny City Clay Club. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - Henry Alexander Wise to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 37), January 29, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Wise acknowledges a letter from H.M. Brackenridge and writes of a convention held between Mexico and the United States. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Aaron Leggett to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 57), April 2, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Leggett, writing from Washington, D. C., to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, discusses the need for a settlement to a claim that was made against the Mexican government. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Henry Clay to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 121), June 18, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Clay, writing from Ashland, Kentucky, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, recounts a recent tour of the South. He also speaks favorably of his stay with Octavia Le Vert, a former pupil of H.M. Brackenridge's. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Cornelius Darragh to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 83), January 22, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Darragh, writing from Washington, D.C., comments on a new edition of Modern Chivalry. He also discusses problems arising from the proposed annexation of Texas, regarding slavery and Congressional representation. [Darragh was a Pennsylvania representative in Congress and later became the State Attorney General.] 3 p. A.L.S.
  - John Baldwin to H. M. Brackenridge, February 12, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Baldwin, writing from Washington D.C., to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, focuses on the dispute over Mexico's quarterly payments to the United States. He also ponders the annexation of Texas and asks H.M. Brackenridge if he would serve on a proposed commission to Mexico. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Thomas Mellon, March 27, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    H.M. Brackenridge's short note from Tarentum, Pennsylvania, concerns the rental of some houses "on the canal." 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Octavia Walton LeVert to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 126), March 11, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    In this letter from Mobile, Alabama, LeVert reflects on her childhood during which H.M. Brackenridge was her tutor. 4 p. A.L.S.
  - William Henry Litton Earle Bulwer to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 03), March 26, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Bulwer, the British ambassador in Washington, D. C., thanks H.M. Brackenridge for a book and invites him to dinner. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - George Robins Glidden to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 05), July 19, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Writing From Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania, Glidden offers thanks for a letter H.M. Brackenridge published in a newspaper about him. Glidden, an ethnologist and lecturer on topics relating to Egyptian archaeology, also hopes H.M. Brackenridge will visit him so they can talk about archaeology. 4 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Peter Force, November 5, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    H.M. Brackenridge, writing from Tarentum, Pennsylvania, requests source material for a book he is researching. He expresses disdain for the current election and a controversy with Neville B. Craig. 2 p. A.L.S.
  - William Makepeace Thackeray to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 04), February 19, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Thackeray, writing from Washington, D.C., sends an acknowledgement of a note of praise from H.M. Brackenridge for one of his books. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - F.S. Bradford to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 125), March 27, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Bradford, writing on behalf of G.P. Putnam Co. in New York, New York, notifies H.M. Brackenridge that a letter of his had been misplaced. 1 p.
  - Evert A. Duyckinck to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 124), March 31, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Duyckinck, writing from New York City, New York, to Tarentum, Pennsylvania, mentions proposed articles to be written on H.M. Brackenridge and his father, Hugh Henry Brackenridge, for the Cyclopedia of American Literature. 4 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Brantz Mayer, February 1, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    H.M. Brackenridge, writing from Tarentum, Pennsylvania, discusses the antiquities and archaeology related to the Cibola Castles in South America. 4 p.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Brantz Mayer, March 11, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Writing from Tarentum, Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, H.M. Brackenridge requests more of Mayer's publications. He also describes a publication concerning American Indian history. 4 p.
  - Alexander Humboldt to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 01), May 24, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Humboldt, writing in French from Potsdam, New York, to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, reports on recent research on ancient civilizations of the southwest. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Brantz Mayer, October 15, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    H.M. Brackenridge, writing in Tarentum, Pennsylvania, refers Mayer to several publications about the antiquities of the Midwest as well as Central and South America. He also asks for a second copy of Mayer's book. 5 p.
  - Brantz Mayer to H. M. Brackenridge, October 21, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Writing from Baltimore, Maryland, Mayer fills H.M. Brackenridge's request for a second copy of his publication on Aztec and Zapote architecture. He also welcomes H.M. Brackenridge's criticisms on the essay. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Thomas Mellon, October 22, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    The letter, from Tarentum, Pennsylvania, concerns letters of administration for an estate. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Brantz Mayer, October 27, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    From Tarentum, Pennsylvania, H.M. Brackenridge thanks Mayer for sending a copy of his book. H.M. Brackenridge relates his views on ancient Mexican history. 2 p.
  - Ephraim George Squier to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 129), January 22, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Squier, writing from New York, New York, discusses American Indian archaeological matters and various publications. 4 p. A.L.S.
  - Peter Arrell Browne to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 127), January 23, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Browne, writing from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, expects to receive a notice about Hugh Henry Brackenridge. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to Thomas Mellon, March 29, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    H.M. Brackenridge asserts he will help relay Mellon's views in his district. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - Andrew Wylie to H. M. Brackenridge, February 2, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Writing from Washington, D.C., Wylie reminisces about his friendship with H.M. Brackenridge. He also mentions preparations for a visit. 4 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge Letter Draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Only the last page of this letter is present. It concerns Central America. 1 p. A.L.S.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to the "Pseudo-Democratic Party" draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
    This folder contains several drafts of letters addressed to the "Pseudo-Democratic" party. The letter outlines various criticisms of the Democratic Party. 20 p.
  - H. M. Brackenridge to the Washington Gazette draft (LB # 06), undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    In this draft, H.M. Brackenridge responds to several critical articles that were published about him in various newspapers. 12 p.
  - William Eichbaum to H. M. Brackenridge (LB# 60), undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Eichbaum reports on recent scientific discoveries such as artificial stone and magnetic paint. 2 p. A.L.S.
- Brackenridge Family Correspondence, 1821-1857; II.